David Mozersky African Union High-Level Implementation Panel Papers MS205
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
David Mozersky African Union High-Level Implementation Panel Papers
2010 -- 2012
1956 -- 2012
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
African Union High-Level Implementation Panel for Sudan
Mozersky, David
MS205
573 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are noted in the Detailed Contents List in each series.
Arrangement
This series is organized into five series: Border Committee files; Cluster group reports; Memorandums; Sudan post-referendum negotiation files; and RAND-HU research papers.
Biographical / Historical
David Mozersky received his B.A. from the University of Western Ontario and his M.A. in Political Science and International Relations from the University of Toronto. He is the Director of the Investments team at Humanity United. David has been involved in conflict-prevention and resolution efforts since 2001. His interest is in mediation, negotiation, and peace processes. From 2010 to 2011 David was seconded from Humanity United to the African Union High Level Implementation Panel on Sudan (AUHIP) as an adviser to the mediation team.
David worked for six years with the International Crisis Group until 2008. He was the Horn of Africa project director and led programs on Sudan, Chad, Ethiopia-Eritrea, and Somalia. His interest is primarily in mediation, negotiation, and peace processes. In 2008, he became the Director of the Investments team at Humanity United.
From 2010 to 2011 David was seconded from Humanity United to the African Union High Level Implementation Panel on Sudan (AUHIP) as a senior advisor to the panel. He worked primarily on border and economic issues.
Custodial History
This collection was transferred from Dave on a thumb drive to the World Peace Foundation. The DCA copied the files from the World Peace Foundation's network drive to our facilities for archival management.
This collection was part of a series of collections the World Peace Foundation collected as part of their grant "Documentation, Research and Writing on the African Union High Level Implementation Panel for Sudan" funded by the United States Institute of Peace.
Related Materials
MS201, Alex de Waal African Union High Level Implementation Panel papers, DCA
MS206, Laura James African Union High-Level Implementation Panel papers, DCA
MS207, Neha Erasmus African Union High-Level Implementation Panel papers, DCA
Scope and Contents
This collection contains agreements, proposals, reports, meeting minutes, agendas, correspondence, and talking points collected and created by Dave Mozersky as an adviser to the African Union High Level Implementation Panel (AUHIP) and a representative from Humanity United from 2010 to 2012. Most of the documents relate to topical cluster groups who were tasked with focusing on specific issues on which the panel was advising. Mozersky's papers focus on Border and Economic issues.
Foreign affairs; African Union; Social justice; Social justice
- Border Committee files, 1956 -- 2011; 2010 -- 2011; MS205.001; 21 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains agreements and research papers relating to the issues discussed by the African Union High Level Implementation Panel on border contentions between Sudan and South Sudan.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - Agreements, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.001.00001
    Open for research.
    - Misseriya and Dinka Ngok Conference Agreement, 2011-01-13; MS205.001.00002
      Conference agreement of negotiations between delegates of the Misseriya and Dinka Ngok tribes, after clashes between those tribes led to the loss of lives and properties.
      Abyei (Sudan); Ngok Dinka (African People); Restorative justice; Misseriya (African People); Conflict Management
    - Common Code of Conduct for the Referenda and Popular Consultations, 2010-10; MS205.001.00003
      The Common Code of Conduct for all political parties, organisations, Political Parties' Councils, and other bodies which agree to be bound by its provisions with respect to their activities connected to: (i) the Southern Sudan Refeendum on Self determination; (ii) the Abyei Referendum to determine the administrative states of Abyei; (iii) the Popular Consultation in Blue Nile State; (iv) the Popular Consultation in South Kordofan.
      Nīl al Azraq (Sudan); Kurdufān al-Janūbīyah (Sudan); Popular consultations; South Sudan--Referendum
    - Guiding Principles on Post 2011 Referendum Arrangements Negotiations, 2010-07-20; MS205.001.00004
      Page 1
      South Sudan--Referendum; Post-secession arrangements; Comprehensive Peace Agreement between the Government of the Republic of Sudan and the Sudan People's Liberation Movement, Sudan People's Liberation Army (2005); National Congress Party; Sudan People's Liberation Movement
    - Guiding Principles on Post 2011 Referendum Arrangements Negotiations, 2010-07-20; MS205.001.00005
      Page 2
    - Mekelle Memorandum of Understanding between the NCP and SPLM on Post-Referendum Issues and Arrangements, 2010-06-23; MS205.001.00006
      Agreement about the modalities and structures for future discussions on the post-referendum issues.
      Mek'el_ (Ethiopia); Secession--South Sudan; Self-determination, national; Peace negotiations; National Congress Party; Sudan People's Liberation Movement
  - Border Committee documents, 1956 -- 2011; MS205.001.00007
    75 years from the date of creation.
    - The Boundary Technical Committee Between North Sudan and its Southern Part - Areas of Disagreement, 1956-01-01; MS205.001.00008
    - The Technical Committee fot the Demarcation 1/1/1956 between North and South Sudan, 2011-04-04; MS205.001.00009
    - The Technical Committee fot the Demarcation 1/1/1956 between North and South Sudan (Arabic), 2011-04-04; MS205.001.00010
  - Concordis papers, 2010; MS205.001.00011
    - Cross-Border Relations Beyond the Referendum: Compiled Recommendations of State-Level Workshops, 2010-03 -- 2010-08; MS205.001.00012
      The cross-border relations project is a peacebuilding initiative financed by the European Commission. This document summarizes the recommendations of 7 workshops held in federal states lying along the border between Northern and Southern Sudan.
      Interregionalism--Sudan; Borderlands; Concordis International; Centre for Peace and Development Studies, University of Juba; European Commission
  - Tamazuj documents, 2010; MS205.001.00013
    - Ten States Conference Briefing, 2010-02-02; MS205.001.00014
    - The Second Conference of Tamazuj (Intermingling) States North Bahr Al Ghazal State - Final Communique and Reconmmendations, 2010-07-14 -- 2010-07-15; MS205.001.00015
      The conference is a continuation of the previous Roundtable Conferences held in Merowe and Wau towards reinforcement of the decisions of the first Tamazuj states' conference held in Kadugli in February 2010. The aim of the conference is to assess the performance progress and to get acquainted with decisions, implementation status as well as overcoming impediments.
      Northern Bahr el Ghazal State (South Sudan)
    - First Reflections Forum for Tamazuj States Towards Peace, Tamazuj and Development - Draft Agenda, 2010-02-15 -- 2010-02-16; MS205.001.00016
    - The First Consultative Meeting for the bordering states' State of South Kordofan_Kadugli - The Final Statement and Recommendations, 2010-02-27 -- 2010-02-28; MS205.001.00017
  - UK white paper on disputed areas, 2011; MS205.001.00018
    - Annex A: Technical Background for the interpretation fo the 1/1/56 boundaries, 2011-12-03; MS205.001.00019
    - Annex A: Technical Background for the interpretation fo the 1/1/56 boundaries, 2011-12-03; MS205.001.00020
    - Resolution of the disputed areas of the North/South border, 2011-01-24; MS205.001.00021
    - Resolution of the disputed areas of the North/South border, 2011-01-24; MS205.001.00022
    - Resolution of the disputed areas of the North/South border, 2011-01-24; MS205.001.00023
      Page 3
    - Resolution of the disputed areas of the North/South border, 2011-01-24; MS205.001.00024
      Page 4
    - Resolution of the disputed areas of the North/South border, 2011-01-24; MS205.001.00025
      Page 5
    - Resolution of the disputed areas of the North/South border, 2011-01-24; MS205.001.00026
      Page 6
- Cluster group reports, 1998 -- 2011; MS205.002; 84 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains proposals, updates, reports, and analyses presented by the cluster groups of the African Union High Level Implementation Panel. These cluster groups include topics on Borders, Citizenship, Currency, Debts and Assets, Economics, Legal issues and treaties, Oil, Security, and Water.
  - Abyei, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.002.00001
    - Security Cluster Action Points Abyei, 2011-01-21; MS205.002.00002
    - Background on Abyei: Evolution of the Abyei negotiations, agreements and implications, 2010-12-11; MS205.002.00003
    - Meeting Brainstorming Abyei, 2010-10-27; MS205.002.00004
    - Proposals, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.002.00005
      - Interim Security Force for Abyei, 2011-05-22; MS205.002.00006
      - Abyei Proposal, 2010-11-08; MS205.002.00007
      - AUHIP Proposals Towards A Resolution of the Issue of Abyei, 2010-11-27; MS205.002.00008
      - AUHIP Proposals Towards A Resolution of the Issue of Abyei, 2010-11-27; MS205.002.00009
      - National Congress Party and Sudan People's Liberation Movement Agreement on Abyei Area Referendum Arrangements, 2010-10-09; MS205.002.00010
      - National Congress Party and Sudan People Liberation Movement Agreement on Abyei Area Arrangements Following the Conclusion of the CPA Interim Period, 2010-09; MS205.002.00011
  - African Union High-level Implementation Panel updates, 2010; MS205.002.00012
    - Economic cluster meeting (AUHIP, World Bank, AEC, US, Norway), 2010-11-08; MS205.002.00013
    - Update on the status of the post-referendum negotiation cluster meetings, 2010-09-20; MS205.002.00014
    - Update on the status of the post-referendum negotiation cluster meetings, 2010-09-28; MS205.002.00015
    - Update on the status of the post-referendum negotiation cluster meetings, 2010-09-30; MS205.002.00016
    - Update on the status of the post-referendum negotiation cluster meetings, 2010-10-01; MS205.002.00017
    - Post referendum negotiation cluster groups: progress report 19/10/10, 2010-10-18; MS205.002.00018
  - Borders, 1998 -- 2011; MS205.002.00019
    - Border Cluster Draft Demarcation Agreement, 2010-10-27; MS205.002.00020
    - Border Cluster Working Draft Demarcation Agreement, 2010-10-27; MS205.002.00021
    - Border Draft Proposal, 2010-10-28; MS205.002.00022
    - Introductory note on AUHIP proposal on border issues, 2010-12-17; MS205.002.00023
    - Status update on North/South border demarcation (Meeting with UNMIS 11/30, UK 12/1, Border Commission Chair 12/2), 2010-12-06; MS205.002.00024
    - Cluster Group Borders meeting minutes, 2010-10-26; MS205.002.00025
    - Draft Agreement on Border Issues, 2010-12-15; MS205.002.00026
    - Draft Agreement on Border Issues, 2010-12-17; MS205.002.00027
    - Ecowas Transhumance Agreement 1998, MS205.002.00028
      This decision sets out the main principles of the rules governing transhumance within ECOWAS Member States
      Transhumance; Economic Community of West African States
    - Framework Border Language, 2010-12-09; MS205.002.00029
    - Soft Border Draft, 2010-12-10; MS205.002.00030
    - Border governors convening AUHIP, 2011; MS205.002.00031
      - Concept Note for Convening the Border Governors Feb 19-20, 2011-01-30; MS205.002.00032
      - Concept Note for Convening the Border Governors Feb 19-20, 2011-02-01; MS205.002.00033
      - Agenda: Soft borders brainstorming, 2011-01-30; MS205.002.00034
      - Talking Points for Meetings with the Governors, 2011-02-01; MS205.002.00035
  - Citizenship, 2010; MS205.002.00036
    - Commitments on Citizenship and Residency Issues Final Draft, 2010-10-29; MS205.002.00037
    - Specific Commitments on Nationality, Citizenship and Related Issues Draft, 2010-12-16; MS205.002.00038
    - Draft UN Recommendations on Citizenship Principles in the case of Secession of South Sudan, 2010-10-24; MS205.002.00039
  - Currency, 2010; MS205.002.00040
    - Currency Draft Proposal, 2010-10-28; MS205.002.00041
    - Currency, Assets and Debts, Water sub-group meeting, Oct. 26 AEC, 2010-10-26; MS205.002.00042
    - Currency Issue Brief for Addis Ababa Talks, 2010-10-25; MS205.002.00043
    - Post-2011 Currency Brief, 2010-09-26; MS205.002.00044
  - Debts and assets, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.002.00045
    - Meeting notes of Economic Cluster, 2010-11-08; MS205.002.00046
    - Assets and Liabilities Issue Brief for Addis Ababa Talks, 2010-10-26; MS205.002.00047
    - Draft Proposal on Assets and Liabilities, 2010-10-30; MS205.002.00048
    - African Development Bank and World Bank IMF seminar, 2010; MS205.002.00049
      - Sudan Debt Workshop: The IMF's Arrears Strategy and Country Experiences, 2010-12-12; MS205.002.00050; Powell, Robert
      - Sudan Debt Workshop: Debt Apportionment, 2010-12-12; MS205.002.00051; Erasmus, Lodewyk
      - Framework for Arrears Clearance Under the Fragile State Facility - Sudan Debt Workshop, 2010-12-12; MS205.002.00052; African Development Bank Group (AFDB)
      - Sudan External Debt Issues - Technical Workshop, 2010-12-12; MS205.002.00053; World Bank
      - Debt Relief Mechanisms: Traditional and HIPC-MDRI, 2010-12-12; MS205.002.00054; Beddies, Christian
      - Poverty Reduction Strategy in Sudan: Interim-PRSP and PRSP, 2010-12-12; MS205.002.00055; World Bank
    - Sudan Debt Dynamics: Status Quo, Southern Secession, Debt Division, and Oil - A Financial Framework for the Future, 2010-12; MS205.002.00056; Leo, Benjamin
      This paper analyses the ongoing discussions about the role of Sudan's $35 billion in external debt obligations - both for a unified Sudan ans a possible Southern secession
      Sudan; South Sudan; Debts, External; Debt relief; Secession--South Sudan; Center for Global Development
    - Assets and Liabilities Issue Brief for Addis Ababa Talks, 2010-10-25; MS205.002.00057
    - Assets and Liabilities Issue Brief for Addis Ababa Talks - revisions by Jeremy Assets, 2010-10-27; MS205.002.00058
    - External debt in the post-2011 negotiations, 2010-09; MS205.002.00059; James, Laura
    - World Bank IMF Spring Meetings, 2011; MS205.002.00060
      - Aid Architecture for South Sudan, 2011-05-12; MS205.002.00061; Saba, Joseph
      - Sudan Roundtable Participants List (provisional) for World Bank Meeting in Washington, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00062
      - Statement by H.E. Ali Mahmoud Abdel Rasoul, Minister of Finance and National Economy, Sudan Roundtable Spring during Meetings, 2011, 2011-04-18; MS205.002.00063
      - Talking Points for Obiageli K. Ezekwesili, VP, Africa Region, World Bank/IMF 2011 Spring Meetings Round Table on Sudan, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00064
      - Draft Summary World Bank/African Development Bank Round Table on Sudan, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00065
      - Speaking Points for H.E. Minister David Deng Athorbei, Sudan Roundtable, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00066
      - Vulnerability and Resilience: The Challenge of Service Delivery in South Sudan, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00067; Srinivasan, Radhika
      - World Bank and African Development Bank Urge Sudan to Resolve Issues and Pledge Support for Broad Based Development, 2011-04-17; MS205.002.00068
        Press release of the third Roundtable on Sudan.
        Sudan; South Sudan; Debts, External; Economic development--International cooperation; World Bank. Financial and Private Sector Development. Non-Bank Financial Institutions.; International Monetary Fund
      - Statement by President Thabo Mbeki during Sudan Roundtable Discussions, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00069
      - Co-Chairs Summary on Sudan Debt Relief, Sudan Roundtable, 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00070
      - Provisional Agenda for Round Table on Sudan, 2011-04-15; MS205.002.00071
      - Progress Update on the Southern Sudan Development Plan (SSDP), 2011-04-16; MS205.002.00072; Sabuni, Aggrey Tisa
  - Economics, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.002.00073
    - NCP/SPLM Economic Cluster Meeting Notes, 2011-02-08; MS205.002.00074
    - Guiding Principles for Finance, Economic and Natural Resources Working Group (Cluster) - NCP/GoS - SPLM/GoSS Post 2011 Referendum Arrangement Negotiations, 2010-07-20; MS205.002.00075
  - Legal issues and treaties, 2010; MS205.002.00076
    - Legal Issues Working Group - Joint Exposure Session - Legal Issues, 2010-10-17; MS205.002.00077
    - Legal issues Working Group - Some Issues, 2010-10-17; MS205.002.00078
  - Negotiating teams, 2010; MS205.002.00079
    - Government of Southern Sudan Presidential Order Number 09/2010: Formation a Committee for Post-referendum Arrangements Negotiations, 2010-07-18; MS205.002.00080
    - NCP Negotiating Team List of Participants for Exposure Workshop in Juba, 2010-07-19 -- 2010-07-20; MS205.002.00081
  - Oil, 2010; MS205.002.00082
    - Tangible Transparency: Ensuring a Transparent and Verifiable Oil Deal in Sudan - Annex: Suggested Transparency Language for New Oil Deal, 2010-10; MS205.002.00083; Global Witness (Organization)
      Suggested guiding principles for the management of the oil sector.
      Sudan; Petroleum industry and trade; Global Witness
    - Tangible Transparency: Ensuring a Transparent and Verifiable Oil Deal in Sudan, 2010-10; MS205.002.00084; Global Witness (Organization)
      The paper provides suggestions for ways in which a new, post-referendum oil deal between north and south Sudan could be made as transparent as possible in order to ensure that the deal is stable and that any tension and mistrust between the two sides is minimised.
    - Oil Cluster Group Summary and Pinciples, 2010-10-26; MS205.002.00085; Embassy of Norway
    - Final Draft Commitments on the Petroleum Sector, 2010-10-28; MS205.002.00086
    - Oil Cluster Group Meeting Notes, 2010-10-26; MS205.002.00087; Embassy of Norway
  - Public International Law and Policy Group, 2009; MS205.002.00088
    - Southern Sudan: A Guide to Critical Post-2011 Issues, 2009-12; MS205.002.00089; Public International and Policy Group
      The Report aims to prepare Sudan for the situation after the 2011 Referendum, and looks into issues of wealth sharing, the rights of transboundary populations, inter-state agreements, etc.
      Secession--South Sudan; Borderlands; Citizenship; Self-determination, national; Autonomy; Petroleum industry and trade; Economic development--International cooperation; Public International Law and Policy Group
  - Security, 2010; MS205.002.00090
    - Sudan Post Referendum Arrangements Exposure Session 20 July 2010 - Framework for Discussion/Agenda, 2010-07-21; MS205.002.00091
    - Elaborated Principles and Mechanisms for Ensuring Mutual Security, 2010-10-29; MS205.002.00092
    - Security Cluster Group Final Draft on Blue Nile State, South Kordofan State and Popular Consultations, 2010-10-29; MS205.002.00093
    - Minutes of Security Cluster Joint Exposure Workshop, 2010-07-21; MS205.002.00094
  - Blue Nile State, South Kordofan State, and Popular Consultations, 2010; MS205.002.00095
    - Issue Brief for Addis Ababa Talks - The Two Areas (SKS and BNS), 2010-10-26; MS205.002.00096
    - The Two Areas (SKS and BNS) - Proposed Text for Framework Agreement, 2010-10-28; MS205.002.00097
    - Suggested Language for Agreement on Blue Nile State, South Kordofan State, and Popular Consultations, 2010-10-29; MS205.002.00098
    - Letter to Mr. Hille Markarious, UNMAS/SRG on Popular Consulation Process in Transitional Areas, 2010-11-16; MS205.002.00099
  - Water, 2010; MS205.002.00100
    - Draft Proposal on Water, 2010-10-29; MS205.002.00101
    - Issue Brief for Addis Ababa Talks - Water, 2010-10-25; MS205.002.00102
- Memorandums, 2010 -- 2011; MS205.003; 11 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains internal memorandums, reports, and letters requesting financial assistance generated by meetings of the members of the African Union High Level Implementation Panel.
  - AUHIP: Status of Border Issues and Next Steps, 2010-01-17; MS205.003.00001
  - Letter from Thabo Mbeki to H.E. Vice President Ali Osman Taha on the escalations in Abyei, 2011-05-29; MS205.003.00002
  - Concept Note: Developing a "Soft Border" - Promoting the Idea of a Shared-rights zone, and Strengthening North-South conomic Cooperation, 2010-10-02; MS205.003.00003
  - Request for assistance, 2010; MS205.003.00004
    - Draft letter from AUHIP to African Development Bank on economic seminar and request for an expert on debts and assets, 2010-12-20; MS205.003.00005
    - Draft letter from AUHIP to he Executive Director of African Development Bank on support for post-referendum negotiations, 2010-12-25; MS205.003.00006
    - Draft Letter from AUHIP to H.E. Ali Osman Taha on assistance for post-referendum negotiating process, 2010-12-12; MS205.003.00007
    - Draft Letter from AUHIP to Dominique Strauss-Kahn, IMF, to request assistance on post-referendum negotiations, 2010-11-21; MS205.003.00008
    - Suggestions for IMF Letter by Laura, 2010-11-21; MS205.003.00009
    - Draft Request from AUHIP to the Government of Norway on Assistance in the Oil Sector, 2010-11-09; MS205.003.00010
    - Draft Letter from AUHIP to Robert Zoellick, President of the World Bank, to request assistance on post-referendum negotiations, 2010-11-21; MS205.003.00011
  - Position of the Sudanese Government on the Issues of Post-Referendum Sector Arrangements and Pending Matters, 2011-05-31; MS205.003.00012
- Sudan Post-referendum negotiation files, 1998 -- 2012; MS205.004; 405 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains strategies, analyses, research, agreements, reports, and agendas relating to the African Union High Level Implementation Panel's involvement in Sudan's Post-referendum mediation. These mediation efforts intended to resolve lingering issues following the Comprehensive Peace Agreement's referendum on South Sudanese independence.
  - Annotated Agenda for Lead Panel Meeting, 2010-11-22; MS205.004.00001
  - Agenda with Questions, 2010-11-22; MS205.004.00002
  - Mekelle Memorandum of Understanding Between the NCP and SPLM on Post-Referendum Issues and Arrangements, 2010-06-22; MS205.004.00003
    Agreement between the NCP and SPLM on the modalities for discussion of post-2011 referendum issues.
    Secession--South Sudan; Self-determination, national; Peace negotiations; Sudan People's Liberation Movement; National Congress Party
  - AU PRI Strategy Paper - Sudan's Post Referendum Negotiations: Injecting a Sense of Urgency, 2010-09-18; MS205.004.00004
  - AUHIP Internal Confidential Update Memo, 2011-05-10; MS205.004.00005
  - Draft of African Union negotiation strategy, 2010-10-16; MS205.004.00006
  - Outstanding Issues in the CPA and Post-Referendum Negotiations - Plan of Action, 2010-11-21; MS205.004.00007
  - Proposed Agenda for Meeting of AUHIP and SPLM/NCP Lead Panel, 2010-11-26; MS205.004.00008
  - Resource Requirements for the Negotiations/AUHIP, 2010-10-15; MS205.004.00009
  - Resource Requirements for the Negotiations/AUHIP, 2010-10-15; MS205.004.00010
  - Letter from Pagan Amum (Chair SPLM/GoSS Negotiation Team) to H.E. President Thabo Mbeki (Chairperson AUHIP) - Proposed Resumption of Post 2011 Arrangement Negotiations, 2011-09-17; MS205.004.00011
  - Economic negotiations strategy, 2009 -- 2011; MS205.004.00012
    - ABD Planning meeting, 2011; MS205.004.00013
      - Draft Agenda for Economic Dialogue, 2011-02-02; MS205.004.00014